Angie Nishikihama B.A., B.F.A. (Hons), M.F.A.

LinkedIn Profile ■ angie.nishikihama@gmail.com

Career Profile

Accomplished professional with 15+ years' experience in print and digital editing, writing, proofreading, and researching. Edited, fact checked, proofread, and coordinated the printing and digital publication of a wide variety of marketing and advertising materials, reports, financial documents, and papers for financial institutions, government offices, and medical and telecommunications companies. Clients have included CIBC, RBC, Miller Lite, Honda/Acura, Telus, Bruce Mau Design, Thomson, and the AGO. Motivated to contribute expertise and genuine passion for words and images to effective communication and understanding. Currently pursuing Certificate in Web Writing & Social Media Communication at the University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies.

work experience

JUNIPER PARK\TBWA, Toronto, Ontario

Senior Proofreader/Editor/Brand Compliance Officer/Production Coordinator

2011-Present

- proofread and edit copy decks, print and digital advertisements, the agency website, and requests for proposals to ensure accuracy of spelling and grammar
- · verify that text and images in print advertisements correspond with client websites
- ensure that all revisions and directions from clients, creative, and account representatives are implemented for final quality control check
- monitor legal disclosure and other requirements, and request any necessary permissions
- · manage brand compliance for at least eight active accounts
- · prepare, update, and revise copy decks; compare English and French copy decks to ensure correlation
- · source materials and contact manufacturers
- verify specifications, material due dates, and FTP submission sites with printers to create publication schedules for studio artists
- · oversee and perform press approvals

ELECTIONS ONTARIO, Toronto, Ontario

Proofreader/Editor (English) (contract)

201

- sole responsibility for editing, rewriting, and proofreading print and web-based materials, including training
 manuals and assignments, marketing materials, letters, internal handbooks, and practice and procedural
 documents
- applied plain and clear writing principles to public-facing materials
- · developed and maintained Elections Ontario's style and lexicon
- identified and queried discrepancies within and across documents, forms, company policies, training manuals, and assignments to create a consistent style

BOWNE OF CANADA, Toronto, Ontario

Proofreader/Copy Editor

2005-2011

- proofread and copy edited a wide range of printed materials for major corporate clients, checking for consistency, flow, readability, and spelling/grammatical accuracy according to Canadian, U.S., and European English standards
- reviewed and corrected content through all prepress stages, from original lasers to plotter proofs and final stage press sheets
- keen eye for detail, identifying font discrepancies, text reflow, and problems with layout, artwork, page breaks, headers/footers, rules, logos, trapping, overprinting, photo dimensions, trademarks, colour consistency, and text/image density
- managed high volume of work under tight deadlines and identified critical content errors in materials encompassing product catalogues, annual reports, and multi-million-dollar marketing campaigns
- reviewed and edited all 2008 Honda and Acura brochures in response to massive errors and reprint costs over previous years as part of a secondment by a leading Toronto advertising agency
- identified and corrected errors in design, text, and content; monitored consistency between, and accuracy of, English and French versions
- ensured correctness of images and placement of artwork
- cross-referenced descriptions and specifications to confirm correspondence within and among marketing materials
- applied, updated, and maintained internal Honda and Acura style manual

Freelance Editor/Proofreader/Researcher

1995-2011

- copy edited and proofread research papers
- · coordinated the production of law reports and publications across the full spectrum of legal specialties
- checked spelling, grammar, punctuation, style, and content, input corrections, queried inconsistencies in content, applied and maintained style, coordinated workflow with team members, and conducted final quality control check
- restructured content and researched quotations, references, and citations
- ensured consistency in text, style, and design between English and French versions
- · met all deadlines and developed a reputation for superior accuracy and commitment to quality
- publications have included "Controversies in Global & Political Societies," "The Canadian Cancer Research Alliance's Survey of Government and Voluntary Sector Investment in Cancer Research," and Administrative Law Reports, among others

THOMSON CARSWELL, Toronto, Ontario

Production Editor

1991-1995

- promoted to manage the publication of more than 35 volumes of *Reports of Family Law* and *Canadian Cases on Employment Law*.
- · completed all editing, proofreading, and research of judgments, annotations, and articles
- · managed production through all proofing and production stages
- · routinely interacted with authors, judges, and lawyers to clarify facts and resolve editorial problems
- · researched case citations, statutes, authorities, and quotations
- worked with editor-in-chief on up to six annotations per volume

Editorial Assistant 1990–1991

• responsible for production coordination of the monthly report Canadian Cases on Employment Law, including editing, proofreading, and research

other experience

ONTARIO COLLEGE OF ART & DESIGN – Faculty of Foundation Studies, Toronto, Ontario Class Assistant – "Creative Process & Research"

Winter 2003/2004

UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH – School of Fine Art and Music, Guelph, Ontario Graduate Teaching Assistant – "Visual Studies in Media and 3-D"

Winter 2002/2003, Fall 2003

INFOMART LIMITED, Toronto, Ontario **Database Indexer** (part time)

1999-2002

education

Writing for the Web (course), University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies	2017
Build a One-Page Website from Scratch (workshop)	2017
Responsive Design for Beginners: Build Mobile Friendly Websites with HTML5 & CSS3 (workshop)	p) 2016
Copywriting that Sells (course), University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies S	ummer 2016
Master of Fine Art, University of Guelph, Guelph	2004
Fine Art Cultural Studies, York University, Toronto	2001-2002
Bachelor of Fine Art (Honours), OCAD University, Toronto	2008
Certificate in Publishing, Ryerson University, Toronto	1993
Bachelor of Art – English and Art History, University of Toronto, Toronto	1990